<!-- The syntax is described by share/Scripts/CheckParam.pl and the manual -->

<commandList name="RAM_SCB: IM Component">

List of IM commands used in the PARAM.in file

<set name="NameRestartOutDir" type="string" value="$_NameComp/restartOUT"/>
<set name="NamePlotDir"       type="string" value="$_NameComp/plots"/>

<commandgroup name="OPERATIONAL MODE">
<command name="SHIELDSRC">

#SHIELDSRC

This command activates \textbf{SHIELDS-RC} mode, an operational version of 
RAM-SCB and the Ring Current portion of the SHIELDS project.  This mode is best
suited for long term simulations with operational implications (e.g. monitoring
$D_{st}$, satellite-specific charging environments, etc.)

In this mode,
\begin{itemize}
	\item SCB is deactivated and a simple dipole magnetic field is used.
	\item $K_{P}$-based Volland-Stern electric field is used.
	\item Only LANL Geosynchronous flux files can be used for
	      the plasma outer boundary conditions.
	\item No full-domain flux files are saved.
	\item Log file write frequencies are lowered to five minutes.
	\item Variable time steps are used.
	\item Output files use date/time naming scheme to prevent overwriting.
\end{itemize}
These options can NOT be altered in SHIELDS-RC mode.
</command>
</commandgroup>

<commandgroup name="STAND ALONE">
!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
!!!!!!!!Stand-alone group!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!

These commands should only be used in Stand-Alone mode.  Many, if not all,
have analogs in the SWMF PARAM system.  If that is the case, RAM-SCB will
get values from those commands.

<command name="DESCRIPTION" multiple="T">
	<parameter name="StringDescription" type="string" length="100" />

#DESCRIPTION
Simulation of the Sep. 1st, 2005 storm.

The StringDescription string can be used to describe the simulation 
for which the parameter file is written. The #DESCRIPTION command and 
the StringDescription string are saved into the restart file, 
which helps in identifying the restart files.  It is often added to
NetCDF files to help describe the output.

</command>

<command name="STARTTIME">
	<parameter name="iYear" type="integer" min="0" default="0" />
	<parameter name="iMonth" type="integer" min="0" default="0" />
	<parameter name="iDay" type="integer" min="0" default="0" />
	<parameter name="iHour" type="integer" min="0" default="0" />
	<parameter name="iMinute" type="integer" min="0" default="0" />
	<parameter name="iSecond" type="integer" min="0" default="0" />
	<parameter name="fracSecond" type="real" min="0" default="0" />

#STARTTIME
2006			iYear
7			iMonth
19			iDay
0			iHour
0			iMinute
0			iSecond
0.0                     fracSecond

The STARTTIME command sets the integer year, month, day, hour, minute and 
second at which the simulation begins. This command is only used in standalone 
mode and only for the first session.
</command>

<command name="RESTART">
#RESTART

If present, RAM-SCB will restart a simulation using the information stored
in the restart files that the user must place in the {\tt restartIN}
folder in the run directory.  Start time and simulation conditions are read
from the restart files.  This command can not be used with {\tt #STARTTIME}.

See Chapter \ref{subchap:restart} for details on restarting simulations.

</commandgroup>

<command name="STOP" required="$_IsStandAlone" if="$_IsStandAlone">
	<parameter name="MaxIteration" type="integer" min="-1" default="-1" />
	<parameter name="tSimulationMax" type="integer"  min="-1" default="-1" />

#STOP
100			MaxIteration
10  			tSimulationMax [sec]

This command is only used in stand alone mode.

The MaxIteration variable contains the
maximum number of iterations {\it since the beginning of the current run}
(in case of a restart, the time steps done before the restart do not count).
If nIteration reaches this value the session is finished.
The tSimulationMax variable contains the maximum simulation time
relative to the initial time determined by the #STARTTIME command.
If tSimulation reaches this value the session is finished.

Using a negative value for either variables means that the
corresponding condition is  not checked. The default values
are MaxIteration=0 and tSimulationMax = 0, so the #STOP command
must be used in every session.
</command>

<commandgroup name="NUMERICAL SCHEME">
!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
!!!!!!!!Numerics group!!!!!!!!!!!
!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
Options for configuring the schemes and solvers, boundary conditions, 
and other numerical options.

<command name="OUTERBOUNDARY"
	required="$_IsFirstSession" if="$_IsFirstSession">
	<parameter name="NameBoundPlasma" type="string" input="select">
		   <option name="LANL" default="T"/>
		   <option name="SWMF"/>
		   <option name="TM03"/>
	</parameter>
	<parameter name="NameBoundMag" type="string" input="select">
		   <option name="T89C" default="T"/>
                   <option name="TS04"/>
                   <option name="SWMF"/>
                   <option name="LANL"/>
                   <option name="DIPL"/>
		   <option name="DIPS"/>
	</parameter>
	<parameter name="NameDistribution" type="string" input="select">
		   <option name="MAXW" default="T"/>
                   <option name="KAPA"/>
	</parameter>
#OUTERBOUNDARY
LANL		NameBoundPlasma
T89C 		NameBoundMag
MAXW            NameDistribution

Set the outer boundary conditions for RAM-SCB.  Based on these settings, 
different files are expected in the respective input directories to suppy
magnetic field and energy flux at the outer boundary of the codes.

\noindent
\emph{\textbf{Current options for plasma boundary conditions:}}
\begin{enumerate}
	\item \textbf{LANL}: Use fluxes calculated from LANL Geosynchronous
	measurements.  Composition is determined from the Young et al. 
	empirical relationship based on Kp and F10.7.
	\item \textbf{SWMF}: Use fluxes calculated from the Space Weather
	Modeling Framework.  If in coupled mode, values are calculated 
	on-the-fly and no input files are required.
	\item \textbf{TM03}: Use fluxes calculated from the Tsyganenko-Mukai
	plasma sheet empirical model.
\end{enumerate}

\noindent
\emph{\textbf{Current options for magnetic field boundary conditions:}}
\begin{enumerate}
	\item \textbf{DIPS}: Use a simple dipole to constrain the SCB field.
	\item \textbf{DIPL}: Use a simple dipole throughout; no SCB calculation.
	\item \textbf{LANL}: Use LANL geosynchronous magnetic field files.
	\item \textbf{SWMF}: Use the magnetic field from the Space Weather 
	Modeling Framework.  If RAM-SCB is in coupled mode, these values are
	calculated and obtained on-the-fly rather than read from input files.
	\item \textbf{T89C}: Use the Tsyganenko 89c empirical model.  
	As this field depends only on Kp, 
	input files are provided in the RAM-SCB distribution.
	\item \textbf{TS04}: Use the Tsyganenko 2004 empirical model.
\end{enumerate}

\noindent
\emph{\textbf{Current options for plasma distribution shape:}}
\begin{enumerate}
        \item \textbf{MAXW}: Assume a Maxwellian distribution.
	\item \textbf{KAPA}: Assume a Kappa distribution.
\end{enumerate} 

</command>

<command name="MULTISPECIESBCS">
	<parameter name="DoMultiSpeciesBcs" type="logical" default="F"/>
	<parameter name="DoElectrons" type="logical" default="F"/>
#MULTISPECIESBCS
F	DoMultiSpeciesBcs
F	DoElectrons

In standalone mode, it may be desireable to still take advantage of 
multispecies boundary conditions from the Space Weather Modeling Framework
through the use of several .swf files (one for each species desired.)  Use
this command to force this behavior.  Note that it disables the application
of Young et al. composition specification.

In coupled mode, or when the outer boundary plasma conditions are not set 
to SWMF, this command has no effect.

The parameter DoElectrons sets the calculation of the electron distribution.  
Note that the electron version of RAM is still under development.
</command>

<command name="EFIELD" 
	required="$_IsFirstSession" if="$_IsFirstSession">
	<parameter name="NameEfield" type="string" length="4" />
	<parameter name="UseEfInd"   type="logical" default="F"/>
#EFIELD
IESC			NameEfield
F			UseEfInd

Set the source for the convective electric field in RAM-SCB.  The choice made
will set the type of input file required at runtime.

\emph{\textbf{Current options for the electric field:}}
\begin{enumerate}
	\item \textbf{IE89}: SWMF IE-component electric field mapped to the 
	equatorial plane via T89c field lines.
	\item \textbf{IESC}: SWMF IE-component electric field mapped to the 
	equatorial plane via RAM-SCB field lines.
	\item \textbf{VOLS}: $K_{P}$-based Volland-Stern empirical electric 
	field (internal VS calculation).
	\item \textbf{WE01}: Weimer 2001 empirical electric field specified
	at the equatorial plane by user (read from file).
	\item \textbf{WESC}: Weimer 2001 empirical electric field mapped to the
	equatorial plane via RAM-SCB field lines (internal W2K calculation).
\end{enumerate}

The parameter UseEfInd turns the use of induced electric field on or off.  
Default is no induced electric field.

The \textbf{IE89} and \textbf{WE01} options require an additional input file 
for every five minutes of simulation time and at the start time.  These files 
are three-column ascii files that give the potential at each RAM grid point
(Local Time - L-Shell combination).

The \textbf{VOLS} and \textbf{WESC} are \textit{internal} calculations and do
not require these additional files, but carry the requirements of their 
respective underlying models.  The Volland-Stern model requires the $K_{P}$ 
index, which is provided for historical simulations.  The Weimer 2000 empirical
model requires upstream solar wind conditions, which can be obtained from the
OMNI database.  This data must be placed into the run directory in a file 
named \textit{omni.txt}.  

Note that these input files can be obtained 
\href{http://omniweb.gsfc.nasa.gov/form/omni_min.html}{via this web form}.

</command>

<command name="USESCB">
	<parameter name="DoUseScb" type="logical" default="T"/>
	<parameter name="DoWriteB" type="logical" default="F"/>
	<parameter name="DoWriteCur" type="logical" default="F"/>
#USESCB
T	DoUseScb
F       DoWriteB
F       DoWriteCur

This command toggles the use of the 3D Equilibrium Magnetic field code.  
Activation of the 3DEQ creates the Self-Consistent Magnetic Field (SCB) 
version of RAM-SCB.  Default is to use 3DEQ.  If switched off, be sure to
have the hI files available to RAM (from any source you choose) in the 
IM/output_scb directory.

</command>

<command name="USEPLANE_SCB">
	<parameter name="DoUsePlane_SCB" type="logical" default="F"/>
#USEPLANE_SCB
F	DoUsePlane_SCB

Turn on plasmaspheric density calculation based on an updated {\it
Rasmussen et al.} [1993] model.  Further sub-options for the
plasmasphere model are specified in ModRamPl_Ne.f90.

</command>

<command name="USEWPI">
	<parameter name="DoUseWPI" type="logical" default="F"/>
	<parameter name="DoUseBASdiff" type="logical" default="F"/>
	<parameter name="DoUseKpdiff" type="logical" default="F"/>
#USEWPI
F	DoUseWPI
F	DoUseBASdiff
F	DoUseKpdiff

Flag to turn on pitch angle diffusion. The default setting for the 
Kp-based version uses Kp=0 coefficients. Turning this flag on 
interpolates Kp-dependent diffusion coefficents for Kp in the 
range (0-4). For Kp$>$4, the Kp=4 coefficients are used. Different
options are available if selecting DoUseBASDiff.

</command>

<command name="VARIABLEDT">
	<parameter name="DoVariableDt" type="logical" default="T"/>
#VARIABLEDT
T	DoVariableDt

Select between a variable timestep that is governed by the CFL number or 
a semi-static timestep that only decreases during periods of high geomagnetic
activity as determined by the Kp index.  The former will allow the timestep
to grow as large as the CFL number will permit, while the latter will use
a timestep of 5 seconds during low (less than 5) Kp or 1 second during higher
Kp.
</command>

<command name="RAMLIMITER">
	<parameter name="BetaLim" type="float"  min="1" max="2"
		default="1.2"/>
#RAMLIMITER
1.5	BetaLim

Set the beta factor for the MC limiter implemented in RAM.  A value of 1 is
equivalent to using the Min-Mod limiter; a value of 2 is equivalent to the
superbee limiter.  1.5 is the default; many codes that implement this limiter
use a value of 1.5.
</command>

<command name="MAXTIMESTEP">
	<parameter name="MaxHalfStep" type="float" default="5.0"/>
#MAXTIMESTEP
5.0	MaxHalfStep

Set the maximum half time step that can be taken by RAM.  Even if the CFL limit
allows for a larger time step, the code will not surpass the limit set here.
Note that this is the \emph{half} time step taken in the time-splitting scheme;
a full timestep is two times the half time step.  

Default vaule is 5 seconds.
</command>

<command name="SCBSCHEME">
	<parameter name="DecreaseConvAlphaMin" type="float" default="0.01"/>
	<parameter name="DecreaseConvAlphaMax" type="float" default="0.01"/>
	<parameter name="DecreaseConvPsiMin"   type="float" default="0.01"/>
	<parameter name="DecreaseConvPsiMax"   type="float" default="0.01"/>
	<parameter name="BlendAlpha"        type="float" default="0.20"/>
	<parameter name="BlendPsi"          type="float" default="0.20"/>
#SCBSCHEME
0.05	DecreaseConvAlphaMin
0.33	DecreaseConvAlphaMax
0.05	DecreaseConvPsiMin
0.33	DecreaseConvPsiMax
0.20	BlendAlpha
0.20	BlendPsi

Set options for the 3D-Equillibrium solver.  Default values are 0.05 for all
DecreaseConv-type variables, 0.20 for all Blend variables.    
Alpha and Psi refer to the different Euler potential surfaces.  
DecreaseConv variables
set the maximum change in the solution between subsequent iterations before
it is assumed that convergence has been reached.  Blending factors control
the amount of blending of the previous solution with the current one.

If DecreaseConv* max and min values are not the same, the values are scaled
as a function of Kp from the minimum to the maximum.  This increases code
stability as the magnetic field becomes more complex with increased activity.
Scaling is parabolic up to Kp=6.0; see figure below.
Because default Max and Min are identical, no activity-based
scaling occurs until the defaults are changed.

\begin{center}
\includegraphics[scale=0.5]{convbehavior.ps}
\end{center}

</command>
</commandgroup>


<commandgroup name="INPUT/OUTPUT">
!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
!!!!!!!!!!!I/O group!!!!!!!!!!!!!
!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
<command name="NAMEFORMAT">
	 <parameter name="UseNewFormat" type="logical" default=F>
#NAMEFORMAT
F	UseNewFormat

Historically, RAM-SCB output files have the format \textit{prefix_IIII.suffix}
where \textit{IIII} is a four digit integer that gives the number of intervals
passed.  The interval is file specific, often set to five minutes or hours.
This format is simple but useful for marking time passed since the beginning
of the run when examining a single event.  When performing long simulations,
however, this format is not only unwieldy but unfeasible as it ultimately
limits the number of files that can be written.

This command toggles the output file name format from the legacy format 
described above to \textit{prefix_dYYYYMMDD_tHHMNSS.suffix}, where the 
simulation date and time are used to organize and differentiate individual 
files of the same \textit{prefix} and \textit{suffix}.  The default is to use
the legacy system.

\textit{Developer's Note}: Module {\tt ModRamIO.f90} contains tools to 
build file names of both types with minimal effort.
<\command>

<command name="SAVERESTART">
	 <parameter name="DtSaveRestart" type="float" default="3600.0"/>
	 <parameter name-"DoSaveFinalRestart" type="logical" default="T"/>
#SAVERESTART
3600.0		DtSaveRestart
T		DoSaveFinalRestart

Configure when restart files are saved.  The first parameter sets the 
frequency, in seconds, that restart files are saved during a simulation.  The
second parameter toggles saving restarts at the successful completion of a
simulation.  Defaults are shown.

</command>

<command name="LOGFILE">
	 <parameter name="DtWrite" type="float" default="60.0"/>
#LOGFILE
60.0	DtWrite

Specify the write frequency of the RAM-SCB log file.  Default value is shown.
Note that frequent writes for any output file may limit the maximum timestep
taken by RAM-SCB.
</command>

<command name="SAVEFLUX">
	 <parameter name="DoWriteFlux" type="logical" default="F"/>
#SAVEFLUX
F	DoSaveFlux

Toggle writing of equatorial flux values for all pitch angles and energies
to NetCDF file.  These files are powerful research tools but large and may
be undesirable for long simulations.  Default is to not write flux files.

</command>

<command name="DUMP3DFLUX">
	<parameter name="DoDump3dFlux" type="logical" default="F"/>
#DUMP3DFLUX
F	DoDump3dFlux

Toggle the writing of the full 3D (spatial), pitch angle, energy, and species
 dependent flux from RAM-SCB.  Default is to not write these values.

Activating this capability comes with heavy caveats due to the immense size
of these output files.  First, ensure that you have sufficient disk space
as each file is on the order of tens of gigabytes.  Second, be sure to 
compile on a 64-bit machine in a 64-bit compatable mode.  The arrays being
written are so massive that the NetCDF library will choke if it is not in 
64-bit mode.  Finally, be ready for unexpected behavior due to the large
amount of data being processed to file.  At current time, this capability is
best reserved for debugging purposes.  Satellite tracing provides a much
more compact way to sample the distribution function at discrete points.
</command>

<command name="OMNIFILE">
	<parameter name="NameOmniFile" type="string" length="200" default="omni.txt"/>
#OMNIFILE
omni.txt	NameOmniFile

The WESC (Weimer electric field traced along SCB field lines) electric field
selection calculates Weimer's empirical electric field on-the-fly.  To do this,
solar wind inputs are required from the Omni database.  The ascii file that
contains these inputs should either be called "omni.txt" and be located in
the run directory (default behavior) or this command should be used to point
the code in the correct location.
</command>

<command name="SATELLITE" if="$_IsFirstSession">
	 <parameter name="DtOutput" type="float" min="10.0" default="60.0"/>
	 <parameter name="nSatellite" type="integer" min="0" default="0" />
	 <for from="1" to="$nSatellite">
	      <parameter name="NameTrajectoryFile" type="string" length="100"/>
	      <rule expr="-f $NameTrajectoryFile">
			Trajectory file $NameTrajectoryFile must exist
	      </rule>	
	 </for>
         <parameter name="DoUseVAPini" type="logical" default="F"/>
#SATELLITE
60.0            DtOutput
2		nSatellite
satellite1.dat	NameTrajectoryFile
satellite2.dat	NameTrajectoryFile
F               DoUseVAPini

The solution of RAM-SCB can be extracted along a satellite's path as the 
simulation progresses by using the #SATELLITE command.  Simply set the 
number of virtual satellites to be included in the simulation, the
time frequency to write the output in seconds (minimum/default is 10), and
the location of each corresponding Trajectory File.  For each Trajectory File
given, RAM-SCB will produce a NetCDF file containing the solution along
the satellite's trajectory at a time frequency of sixty seconds.  Note that
reducing DtOutput to small values can reduce the maximum RAM-SCB time step as
a result of ensuring that the file is written every DtOutput.

Satellite Trajectory Files contain the trajectory of the satellite.  They should
have the following format:
\begin{verbatim}
#START
 2004  6  24   0   0  58   0  2.9  -3.1 - 3.7  
 2004  6  24   0   1  58   0  2.8  -3.2 - 3.6  
\end{verbatim}

The file containing the satellite trajectory should include data in the 
following order:
\begin{verbatim}
yr mn dy hr min sec msec x y z
\end{verbatim}
with the position variables in units of the body radii or the length scale
normalization.  Note that this is the same format as BATS-R-US trajectory 
files with one
important feature: the position is assumed to be in SM coordinates.  If the 
input coordinates are in another coordinate system, use the #COOR command to
specify what system is used in the file.  RAM-SCB will convert from that 
system to SM.

The maximum number of satellite files allowed is 100.  The maximum
number of lines in a given satellite file (past the #START command)
is 100,000.  Both of these can be changed by editing the value of
MaxRamSat and MaxRamSatLines (respectively) in ModRamSats.f90

Each satellite listed under the #SATELLITE command will produce a 
NetCDF file in the output_ram folder.  Simulation meta data, such as 
run parameters, start times, etc., are contained within this file as well as 
energy and pitch angle grid information.  Magnetic field, flux, spacecraft 
position, and other values are saved for every DtOutput for which the 
satellite is within the 3D Equilibrium code's domain.  Each record written 
takes about ten kilobytes of hard drive space.
</command>

</commandgroup>


<commandgroup name="TESTING">
!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
!!!!!!!!Testing group!!!!!!!!!!!!
!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!

<command name="TEST">
	<parameter name="StringTest" type="string" length="100"/>

#TEST
CON_session::do_session		StringTest

A space separated list of subroutine and function names to be tested. 
Only subroutines containing the 'call CON_set_do_test(...)' statement
can be tested. The first argument is the name of the subroutine,
usually defined as the string parameter 'NameSub'.
Default is an empty string.

This feature and its conventions has been adopted from the Space 
Weather Modeling Framework. 

</command>


</commandgroup>

<commandgroup name="OTHER">
!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
!!!!!!!!!!Other group!!!!!!!!!!!!
!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!!
<command name="INCLUDE">
	<parameter name="NameIncludeFile" type="string" length="100"/>
#INCLUDE
Commands.in	NameIncludeFile

The NameIncludeFile parameter contains the name of the file to be included.
This file can contain any additional PARAM commands and will be included as 
if the text of NameIncludeFile was located within PARAM.in place of the 
#INCLUDE command which points to it. This is useful for organizing large
PARAM.in files into separate, smaller chunks.
The file name may be followed with a trailing comment if it is separated with 
at least 3 spaces or one TAB character. The #INCLUDE command can be used 
anywhere in the parameter file, even in the sections which contain the 
component specific parameters.  
</commandgroup>

</commandList>
